- ARE YOU READY, KIDS?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all: AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN!
所有人：是，是，队长！
- I CAN'T HEAR YOU.
- 我听不到你说话。
all: AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN!
所有人：是，是，队长！
- ♪ OHH...
- ♪ 噢...
♪ WHO LIVES IN A PINEAPPLE
UNDER THE SEA? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all: SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
所有：海绵宝宝！
- ♪ ABSORBENT AND YELLOW
AND POROUS IS HE ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all: SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
所有：海绵宝宝！
- ♪ IF NAUTICAL NONSENSE
BE SOMETHING YOU WISH ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你所希望的 ♪
all: SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
所有：海绵宝宝！
- ♪ THEN DROP ON THE DECK
AND FLOP LIKE A FISH ♪
- ♪ 然后掉到甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
- READY?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all: SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
所有：海绵宝宝！
SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
海绵宝宝！
- SPONGEBOB
- 海绵宝宝
SQUAREPANTS!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
radio announcer: GOOD MORNING,
BIKINI BOTTOM!
广播播音员：早上好，
比基尼泳裤！
IT IS A VERY SPECIAL DAY TODAY
今天是非常特别的一天
BECAUSE WE'VE GOT THE NEW
SINGLE FROM BOYS WHO CRY,
因为我们有新的
哭泣的男孩的单曲，
IT'S ALL ABOUT YOU.
一切都与您有关。
- ♪ IT'S ALL ABOUT YOU, GIRL
- ♪ 这都是关于你的，女孩
♪ ON YOUR 16TH BIRTHDAY
♪ 在你 16 岁生日那天
♪ WE'LL PAY ATTENTION TO YOU,
GIRL ♪
♪ 我们会关注您，
女孩♪
♪ EVERYONE HAS TO DO
JUST WHAT YOU SAY ♪
♪ 每个人都必须做
只要你说的 ♪
♪ YOU'LL GET YOUR VERY OWN
SPOTLIGHT TONIGHT ♪
♪ 你会得到你自己的
今晚的焦点♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S ALL ABOUT YOU
♪ 因为一切都与你有关
♪ YEAH, IT'S ALL ABOUT PEARL
♪ 是的，一切都与珍珠有关
♪ YOU'RE THE BIRTHDAY GIRL
♪ 你就是生日女孩
- YEAH, IT'S ALL ABOUT ME.
- 是的，都是关于我的。
- ♪ YEAH, PEARL
- ♪ 是的，珍珠
- ON MY 16TH BIRTHDAY.
- 在我 16 岁生日那天。
I WANT MUSIC AND CLOTHES
AND SHINY THINGS.
我想要音乐和衣服
和闪亮的东西。
SO GIVE IT UP RIGHT AWAY.
所以请立即放弃。
EVERYBODY
IN THE WHOLE WIDE WORLD
大家
在整个世界
THEY HAVE TO PAY ATTENTION
TO ME.
他们必须注意
对我来说。
IT'S ALL ABOUT ME, ME...
都是关于我的，我的……
AND GUESS WHO.
猜猜是谁。
ME!
我！
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
[gasps]
[喘气]
crash!
碰撞！
- NEPTUNE'S TREASURES!
- 海王星的宝藏！
- MORNING, DADDY.
- 早上好，爸爸。
- ARE YOU SURE YOU WOULDN'T
PREFER A ROOM
- 你确定你不会吗
喜欢一个房间
ON THE GROUND FLOOR?
在一楼？
- OH, DADDY.
- 哦，爸爸。
I'M JUST EXCITED BECAUSE
TOMORROW'S A VERY SPECIAL DAY.
我只是很兴奋因为
明天是非常特别的一天。
- [gulps]
- [吞咽]
IT IS?
这是？
OH, I MEAN, IT IS!
哦，我的意思是，确实如此！
VERY SPECIAL!
非常特别！
VERY, VERY SPECIAL INDEED.
确实非常非常特别。
- YOU HAVE NO IDEA WHAT DAY
TOMORROW IS, DO YOU?
- 你不知道哪一天
明天就是，你呢？
- NONE AT ALL.
- 完全没有。
- IT'S MY 16TH BIRTHDAY!
- 今天是我 16 岁生日！
- I KNEW THAT.
- 我知道这一点。
HOW COULD YOU THINK
I WOULDN'T KNOW THAT?
你怎么会这么想
我不知道吗？
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO BE, 12?
12岁，你想成为什么？
- I'M GOING TO BE 16!
- 我马上就 16 岁了！
IT'S ONLY THE MOST IMPORTANT
BIRTHDAY IN MY ENTIRE LIFE.
这只是最重要的
我一生中的生日。
IF I DON'T HAVE
A COMPLETELY AWESOME PARTY,
如果我没有
一场非常棒的派对，
MY WHOLE HIGH SCHOOL REPUTATION
WILL COLLAPSE.
我整个高中的声誉
将会崩溃。
I'LL HAVE TO DROP OUT.
我必须退学。
I WON'T GO OFF TO COLLEGE.
我不会去上大学。
I'LL NEVER LEAVE HOME.
我永远不会离开家。
YOU'LL HAVE TO SUPPORT ME
FOR THE REST OF MY LIFE.
你必须支持我
在我的余生中。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
WELL,
WE DON'T WANT THAT TO HAPPEN.
嗯，
我们不希望这种情况发生。
- THEN PROMISE ME YOU'LL GIVE
ME A REAL PARTY THIS YEAR.
- 那么答应我你会给予
今年我是一个真正的派对。
AND DON'T BE CHEAP.
并且不要贪图便宜。
[bell ringing]
[铃声响起]
HI, GIRLS.
嗨，女孩们。
- HI, PEARL.
- 嗨，珍珠。
- ARE YOU GUYS COMING
- 你们来吗
TO MY TOTALLY CORAL
BIRTHDAY PARTY TOMORROW?
致我的珊瑚
明天生日派对？
- I DON'T KNOW, PEARL.
- 我不知道，珀尔。
IS THIS GOING TO BE AS TOTALLY
CORAL AS LAST YEAR
这完全是这样吗？
与去年一样的珊瑚色
WHEN YOUR DAD PASSED OUT
PAPER CLIPS AS PARTY FAVORS?
当你爸爸昏倒时
回形针作为派对礼物？
[girls laugh]
[女孩们笑]
- REMEMBER THE TIME
WE ALL HAD TO SHARE ONE BALLOON?
- 记住时间
我们必须共用一个气球？
PLEASE.
请。
- REMEMBER THE PONY RIDE?
- 还记得骑小马吗？
I CAN'T WAIT TO SEE
HOW HE RUINS THIS YEAR.
我等不及要看
他今年是如何毁掉的。
[laughing]
[笑]
- [sobbing]
- [抽泣]
DADDY!
爸爸！
[rumbling]
- UH-OH.
[隆隆声]
- 呃-哦。
EVERYBODY, BRACE FOR IMPACT!
大家，准备好迎接冲击吧！
[rumbling and sobbing,
customers screaming]
[隆隆声和抽泣声，
顾客尖叫]
TELL ME YOU'VE GOT SOMETHING
TOTALLY CORAL
告诉我你有东西
完全珊瑚色
PLANNED FOR MY
BIRTHDAY PARTY.
为我计划的
生日聚会。
- NOW, NOW,
DON'T SNAP YOUR MIZZENMAST.
- 现在，现在，
不要折断你的后桅。
EVERYTHING IS ALL SET.
一切都已准备就绪。
WHY, I'VE ALREADY
GOT THE PARTY FAVORS:
为什么，我已经
得到了派对的青睐：
BUBBLE WRAP!
气泡膜！
THIS YEAR'S GONNA BE A BLAST.
今年将会是爆炸性的一年。
- DADDY, YOU RUINED
ALL MY BIRTHDAY PARTIES.
- 爸爸，你毁了
我所有的生日派对。
BUT YOU BETTER NOT
RUIN THIS ONE.
但你最好不要
毁掉这个。
NOW, PROMISE ME
YOU WON'T BE CHEAP.
现在，答应我
你不会便宜的。
- [gulps]
I PROMISE.
- [吞咽]
我保证。
- GOOD.
- 好的。
BECAUSE I MADE A LIST.
因为我列了一个清单。
NOW, I WANT EVERYTHING
ON THIS LIST AT MY PARTY.
现在，我想要一切
在我的聚会上的这份名单上。
BYE.
再见。
I'LL BE AT THE MALL
WITH MY FRIENDS.
我会去商场
和我的朋友们。
- SPONGEBOB!
- 海绵宝宝！
- YES, MR. KRABS?
- 是的，先生。螃蟹？
- WHILE I PLAN THE PARTY,
- 当我计划聚会时，
I WANT YOU
TO BUY PEARL'S PRESENT.
我想要你
购买珍珠的礼物。
HERE YOU GO, BOY.
给你，男孩。
- WHAT'S THIS, MR. KRABS?
- 这是什么，先生。螃蟹？
- IT'S ME CREDIT CARD.
- 这是我的信用卡。
YOU USE IT INSTEAD OF MONEY.
您用它代替金钱。
- I CAN BUY STUFF
WITH JUST THIS PIECE OF PLASTIC?
- 我可以买东西
就用这块塑料？
I DON'T NEED MONEY?
我不需要钱？
- EXACTLY.
- WHOA.
- 确切地。
- 哇哦。
- NOW REMEMBER, NOTHING'S TOO
GOOD FOR ME LITTLE PEARL.
- 现在记住，没有什么是太
对我有好处，小珍珠。
I WANTED TO GIVE HER NOTHING,
我什么都不想给她，
[mocking tone]
BUT SHE'S TOO GOOD FOR THAT.
[嘲讽语气]
但她太优秀了。
NOW FOLLOW HER AROUND
AND SEE WHAT SHE LIKES.
现在跟随她
看看她喜欢什么。
YOU KNOW,
DO SOME DETECTIVE WORK.
你知道，
做一些侦探工作。
- DETECTIVE WORK.
- 侦探工作。
I'M GOING UNDERCOVER.
我要去卧底。
- SO THAT'S WHEN MARCIE
TOLD ME
- 这就是玛西的时候
告诉我
THAT JULIE SAID
THAT ANGELA DID LIKE BRAD.
朱莉说的
安吉拉确实喜欢布拉德。
- OH.
- 哦。
- ANGELA LIKES BRAD.
- 安吉拉喜欢布拉德。
- OH, MY GOSH!
- 哦，天哪！
THIS IS THE GREATEST THING
I HAVE SEEN
这是最伟大的事情
我见过
IN THE WHOLE WORLD.
在全世界。
- I'D LIKE TO BUY
THAT PIECE OF PLASTIC
- 我想买
那块塑料
WITH THIS PIECE OF PLASTIC.
用这块塑料。
- MR. KRABS, HUH?
- 先生。螃蟹，嗯？
QUICK.
HOW DO YOU SPELL "KRABS"?
快的。
“蟹”怎么拼写？
- UM...
- 嗯...
I'M PRETTY SURE
IT HAS A "B" IN IT.
我很确定
它有一个“B”。
- CLOSE ENOUGH.
- 足够接近。
HERE YOU GO, KID.
给你，孩子。
- THAT'S IT?
HUH.
- 就是这样？
呵呵。
I'LL NEVER UNDERSTAND
THE WORKINGS OF HIGH FINANCE.
我永远不会明白
高金融的运作。
- WOW.
- 哇。
THIS IS THE GREATEST THING
I'VE EVER SEEN
这是最伟大的事情
我见过
IN THE WHOLE WORLD.
在全世界。
GLITTER GLOSS.
闪光光泽。
- OH, NO.
- 哦，不。
I BOUGHT THE WRONG PRESENT.
我买错了礼物。
- PEARL,
YOU HAVE GOT TO SEE THIS.
- 珍珠，
你一定要看看这个。
- COMING, JUDY.
- 来了，朱迪。
- OH...
- 哦...
HMM...
唔...
HUH?
嗯？
- NOW, THIS IS OBVIOUSLY
THE GREATEST PRESENT EVER.
- 现在，这很明显
有史以来最伟大的礼物。
[Pearl squealing]
[珍珠尖叫声]
THIS IS THE GREATEST THING
IN THE WHOLE WORLD!
这是最伟大的事情
在全世界！
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
- THE BANNER'S UP, MR. KRABS.
- 横幅竖起来了，先生。螃蟹。
- I'VE HAD THAT
SINCE THE DAY SHE WAS BORN.
- 我已经这样了
从她出生那天起。
[sniffles]
I GOT IT ON SALE.
[抽鼻子]
我特价了。
- I'M SURE SHE'LL LOVE IT,
MR. KRABS.
- 我相信她会喜欢它，
先生。螃蟹。
- [blows nose]
- [擤鼻子]
- THIS SEA PONY
IS THE CUTEST THING EVER.
- 这头海马
是有史以来最可爱的东西。
DO YOU WANT TO COME HOME
AND BE MY PONY?
你想回家吗
成为我的小马吗？
- [panting]
- WEE!
- [气喘吁吁]
- 哇！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- PEARL, COME HERE.
- 珀尔，过来。
THIS IS SO CORAL.
这太珊瑚了。
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
- OH, MY GOSH.
IT'S BILLY FISHKIN.
- 哦，天哪。
这是比利·菲什金。
all: HI, BILLY.
所有人：嗨，比利。
- MEEP.
- 米普。
[all sighing]
[大家叹气]
- OH, ISN'T HE DREAMY?
- 哦，他不是很梦幻吗？
[scanner beeps]
[扫描仪发出蜂鸣声]
- PRICE CHECK ON FOUR.
- 四点价格检查。
- MEEP.
- 米普。
- I FINISHED PEARL'S PORTRAIT,
MR. KRABS.
- 我完成了《珍珠的肖像》，
先生。螃蟹。
IT'S A TRUE MASTERPIECE.
这是真正的杰作。
- HEY...
- 嘿...
MAYBE I SHOULD HAVE HIRED
THAT ICE SCULPTOR.
也许我应该雇用
那个冰雕师。
- ICE SCULPTOR?
- 冰雕师？
ANY FOOL CAN SCULPT IN ICE.
任何傻瓜都可以在冰上雕刻。
IT TAKES TRUE GENIUS
这需要真正的天才
TO TRANSFORM 400 POUNDS
OF RAW KRABBY PATTIES
变形 400 磅
生蟹肉饼
INTO A WORK OF SUCH MAJESTY.
成为如此宏伟的作品。
- YEAH.
- 是的。
WELL,
WE'VE GOT THE DECOR COVERED.
嗯，
我们已经做好了装饰。
NOW, HOW ABOUT ENTERTAINMENT?
LET ME SEE HERE.
现在，娱乐怎么样？
让我看看这里。
PEARL WANTS SOME BOY BAND
CALLED BOYS WHO CRY.
珀尔想要一些男孩乐队
被称为哭泣的男孩。
- BOYS WHO CRY?
- 哭泣的男孩？
THEY'RE MY FAVORITE BAND.
他们是我最喜欢的乐队。
THEY CHARGE A MILLION DOLLARS
JUST TO SHOW UP.
他们要价一百万美元
只是为了出现。
IF YOU WANT THEM TO LIP-SYNC,
IT'LL RUN INTO REAL MONEY.
如果你想让他们对口型，
它会投入真金白银。
- YOU'RE A REAL FAN, HUH?
- 你是一个真正的粉丝，是吗？
- OH, YEAH.
- 哦，是的。
I KNOW ALL THEIR SONGS.
我知道他们所有的歌曲。
- HMM.
- 唔。
ALL THEIR SONGS?
他们所有的歌曲？
beep!
cha-ching!
嘟！
查清！
beep!
cha-ching!
嘟！
查清！
[beeping and cash register
dinging repeatedly]
[蜂鸣声和收银机
叮叮当当]
- WOULDN'T IT BE COOL IF MY DAD
GOT ME THIS FOR MY BIRTHDAY?
- 如果我爸爸是的话，那不是很酷吗
给我买了这个作为我的生日礼物吗？
- IT SURE WOULD BE,
IF HE WAS COOL...
- 肯定会是，
如果他很酷的话...
WHICH HE'S NOT.
[girls laughing]
但他不是。
[女孩们笑]
- YEAH, HE PROBABLY GOT ME
ANOTHER BOX OF STAPLES.
- 是的，他可能抓住了我
另一盒订书钉。
- IT'S ALMOST TIME
FOR THE PARTY TO START.
- 时间快到了
派对开始。
- I'M BACK, MR. KRABS.
- 我回来了，先生。螃蟹。
- SPONGEBOB,
WHAT TOOK YOU SO LONG?
- 海绵宝宝，
你怎么花了这么长时间？
AND WHERE'S PEARL'S PRESENT?
珀尔现在在哪里？
- THE DELIVERY TRUCK
WILL BE HERE MOMENTARILY.
- 送货卡车
- HERE SHE COMES, MR. KRABS.
- 她来了，先生。螃蟹。
- EVERYBODY GET IN POSITION.
- 每个人都就位。
all: HAPPY BIRTHDAY!
全体：生日快乐！
- "IT'S A BOY"?
- “这是一个男孩”？
[laughing]
[笑]
- DADDY!
- 爸爸！
[all crunching]
[一切都在嘎吱嘎吱]
[all gagging and coughing]
[全都作呕和咳嗽]
- STALE POPCORN.
- 不新鲜的爆米花。
IT TASTES LIKE DISHWATER.
尝起来像洗碗水。
- IT IS DISHWATER.
- 这是洗碗水。
[all gagging and coughing]
[全都作呕和咳嗽]
- IS THAT SUPPOSED TO BE ME?
- 那应该是我吗？
IT'S MADE OUT OF KRABBY
PATTIES.
它是由 KRABBY 制成的
肉饼。
GROSS!
总的！
- WHO WANTS CAKE?
- 谁想要蛋糕？
- WELL, THE CAKE DOES LOOK GOOD.
- 嗯，蛋糕看起来不错。
chomp!
咀嚼！
[gags]
[笑点]
IT'S MADE OUT OF CARDBOARD.
它是用纸板制成的。
- AND FROSTING.
- 和糖霜。
- WOW, PEARL.
- 哇，珍珠。
16 LAME PARTIES IN A ROW.
连续 16 个蹩脚的派对。
MUST BE A NEW RECORD.
一定是一个新记录。
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
我们离开这里吧。
- WAIT.
- 等待。
DON'T LEAVE.
不要离开。
MY DAD GOT BOYS WHO CRY TO PLAY.
我爸爸有一些哭着玩耍的男孩。
YOU DID GET BOYS WHO CRY, RIGHT?
你确实让男孩哭过，对吧？
- OOH, EVEN BETTER, SWEETIE.
- 哦，更好了，亲爱的。
HIT IT.
击中它。
[R&B music begins]
[R&B音乐开始]
- HELLO, LADIES.
- 你好，女士们。
♪ WHEN MY TEAR DUCTS
GIVE ISSUE ♪
♪ 当我的泪管出现时
提出问题♪
♪ I CAN'T USE JUST ANY TISSUE
♪ 我不能只使用纸巾
♪ I NEED FOUR-PLY
♪ 我需要四层
♪ FOUR-PLY
♪ 四层
♪ WHEN I CRY
♪ 当我哭泣时
♪ HUH!
♪ 哈！
- HEY, THAT IS NOT BOYS WHO CRY.
- 嘿，那不是哭泣的男孩。
- YEAH.
- 是的。
- BOO!
- 嘘！
- WHAT A RIP-OFF.
- 真是骗人的。
- THIS STINKS!
- 这太臭了！
- DADDY, HOW COULD YOU?
- 爸爸，你怎么能这样？
I GAVE YOU A LIST.
我给了你一个清单。
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- PEARL, COME BACK.
- 珀尔，回来吧。
smack!
咂！
- YOU RUINED EVERYTHING.
- 你毁了一切。
YOU COULDN'T STOP BEING CHEAP,
EVEN FOR ME.
你无法停止贪图便宜，
即使对我来说也是如此。
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- I'LL MAKE IT UP TO YOU
SOMEHOW, PEARL.
- 我会补偿你的
不知何故，珍珠。
- THAT'S IT!
- 就是这样！
BACK IT UP.
备份。
RIGHT THERE.
就在那里。
LET 'ER GO.
让他走吧。
crash!
碰撞！
- YOU BOUGHT ME A BOAT?
- 你给我买了一条船？
- I DID?
- 我做到了？
I MEAN...
我是说...
I DID?
我做到了？
all: WOW.
所有人：哇。
- OH, DADDY, I DON'T KNOW HOW
IT COULD GET BETTER THAN THIS.
- 哦，爸爸，我不知道怎么办
它可以变得比这更好。
- JUST WATCH.
- 只要看。
HIT IT, BOYS.
打吧，孩子们。
[smooth R&B music begins]
【流畅的R&B音乐开始】
- ♪ IT'S ALL ABOUT YOU, GIRL
- ♪ 这都是关于你的，女孩
♪ ON YOUR 16TH BIRTHDAY
♪ 在你 16 岁生日那天
♪ WE'LL PAY ATTENTION TO YOU,
GIRL ♪
♪ 我们会关注您，
女孩♪
♪ EVERYONE HAS TO DO
JUST WHAT YOU SAY ♪
♪ 每个人都必须做
只要你说的 ♪
♪ YOU'LL GET YOUR VERY OWN
SPOTLIGHT TONIGHT ♪
♪ 你会得到你自己的
今晚的焦点♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S ALL ABOUT YOU
♪ 因为一切都与你有关
♪ YEAH, IT'S ALL ABOUT PEARL
♪ 是的，一切都与珍珠有关
♪ YOU'RE THE BIRTHDAY GIRL
- BOY.
♪ 你就是生日女孩
- 男孩。
HOW MUCH IS ALL THIS COSTING ME?
这一切让我付出了多少代价？
- HERE'S THE RECEIPT.
- [gasps]
- 这是收据。
- [喘气]
[alarm bell rings]
[警钟响起]
I OUGHT TO--
我应该——
- OH, DADDY.
- 哦，爸爸。
YOU GOT ME EVERYTHING I WANTED.
你给了我我想要的一切。
smooch!
接吻！
- AH, NOTHING'S TOO GOOD
FOR ME DAUGHTER.
- 啊，没什么太好的
为了我的女儿。
- YOU'RE A GOOD DAD, MR. KRABS.
- 你是个好爸爸，先生。螃蟹。
- DON'T PUSH YOUR LUCK, BOY.
- 别再碰运气了，孩子。
- OKAY, GARY.
- 好吧，加里。
READY FOR
YOUR YEARLY SHELL-WAXING?
准备好
您每年都会进行贝壳打蜡吗？
- [meows]
- [喵]
[whirring]
[呼呼]
JUST LOOK AT THAT SHINE.
看看那光芒。
NOW, LET'S CHECK
UNDER THE HOOD.
现在，让我们检查一下
引擎盖下。
JEEZ, GARY.
THIS PLACE IS A REAL SNAIL-STY.
天啊，加里。
这个地方是真正的蜗牛窝。
- [meows]
- [喵]
- STILL?
FROM NEW YEAR'S EVE?
- 仍然？
从除夕开始？
- [horn blowing]
- [吹喇叭]
- WHAT?
- 什么？
I'VE BEEN LOOKING EVERYWHERE
FOR THIS, GARY!
我一直在到处寻找
为此，加里！
MY FAVORITE NOVELTY T-SHIRT.
[doorbell rings]
我最喜欢的新奇 T 恤。
[门铃响]
OOH!
SOMEONE'S HERE.
哦！
有人在这里。
- SPECIAL DELIVERY
FOR SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS.
- 特别送货
对于海绵宝宝来说。
- SPECIAL DELIVERY?
- 特别送货？
JUST FOR ME?
只为我？
YOU THINK I'M...
你以为我是...
SPECIAL?
特别的？
[wailing]
[哀号]
- ALL RIGHT,
DO WE HAVE TO GO THROUGH THIS
- 好吧，
我们必须经历这个吗
EVERY TIME I GIVE YOU YOUR MAIL?
每次我给你邮件？
SHEESH!
嘘！
- WHAT COULD IT BE TODAY, GARY?
- 今天会是什么，加里？
- [meows]
- [喵]
- A VIDEOTAPE?
- 录像带？
"YOU'RE A WINNER!
“你是赢家！
SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS."
海绵宝宝。”
I'M SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
我是海绵宝宝！
TV announcer: KARATE ISLAND!
电视播音员：空手道岛！
A SERENE AND EXOTIC LOCATION
宁静而充满异国情调的地方
WHERE NATURE AND BEAUTY ABOUND
充满自然与美丽的地方
AND HUNDREDS OF FIGHTING STYLES
COLLIDE
以及数百种战斗风格
碰撞
IN A WAVE OF NON-STOP,
PULSATING,
一波又一波不停歇的浪潮中，
脉动，
NO-HOLDS BARRED ACTION!
没有任何限制的行动！
FOR CENTURIES,
THE WORLD'S TOP KARATE ARTISTS
几个世纪以来，
世界顶级空手道艺术家
HAVE JOURNEYED TO THIS LAND
TO BE CROWNED KING OF KARATE.
已经到过这片土地
加冕空手道之王。
- KING...
- 国王...
OF KARATE?
空手道？
announcer: NOW IT'S YOUR
TURN...
播音员：现在是你的了
转...
- SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS.
- 海绵宝宝。
announcer: YOU'VE WON
AN ALL-EXPENSE PAID TRIP
播音员：你赢了
一次全费用付费旅行
TO KARATE ISLAND...
去空手道岛...
HIYAH!
嗨！
WHERE YOU WILL BE CROWNED
THIS YEAR'S
您将在哪里加冕
今年的
KING OF KARATE.
空手道之王。
- OOH...
- 哦...
DID YOU HEAR THAT, GARY?
你听到了吗，加里？
I'M GOING TO CROWNED...
我要加冕...
[shouts indistinctly]
[含糊不清地喊道]
KING OF KARATE!
空手道之王！
WHOO-HOO!
呼呼！
HI...
你好...
YAH!
啊！
- HOWDY, SPONGEBOB.
- 你好，海绵宝宝。
- HELLO, SANDY.
- 你好，桑迪。
HAVE YOU HEARD THE NEWS?
您听到这个消息了吗？
I'VE BEEN INVITED
TO KARATE ISLAND
我已被邀请
前往空手道岛
TO BE CROWNED
THE KING OF KARATE.
加冕
空手道之王。
- KARATE ISLAND?
- 空手道岛？
I'VE NEVER HEARD
OF KARATE ISLAND.
我从来没有听说过
空手道岛。
- OH, SURE, SANDY,
- 哦，当然，桑迪，
ALL THE BIG KARATE EXPERTS
GO THERE.
所有大空手道专家
去那里。
- BUT...
- 但...
MY KARATE IS BETTER THAN YOURS
BY A COUNTRY MILE,
我的空手道比你的好
一英里，
AND I'VE NEVER BEEN INVITED.
而且我从未被邀请过。
- MAYBE YOUR KARATE
WAS THE BEST,
- 也许是你的空手道
是最好的，
BUT NOW THEY'VE RECOGNIZED
A NEW NUMBER ONE.
但现在他们已经认识到
新的第一名。
- THERE'S SOMETHING ROTTEN
IN THE ALAMO.
- 有东西腐烂了
在阿拉莫。
I'D BETTER TAG ALONG WITH YOU
我最好和你一起
AND SEE
IF IT'S ON THE UP-AND-UP.
并查看
如果它是向上的。
- ALL RIGHT, SANDY,
- 好吧，桑迪，
YOU CAN COME WITH ME
TO WITNESS MY "CROWNING" MOMENT.
你可以跟我一起去
见证我的“加冕”时刻。
[laughing]
[笑]
ARE WE THERE YET?
我们到了吗？
- YUP, THAT'S IT OVER THERE.
- 是的，就是那边。
- WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
THAT'S KARATE ISLAND?
- 是什么让你这么想
那是空手道岛？
- I DON'T KNOW.
- 我不知道。
LUCKY GUESS?
你猜幸运吗？
- HELLO, THERE,
THE KING OF KARATE HAS ARRIVED.
- 你好，那里，
空手道之王已经到来。
- WELCOME TO MY ISLAND,
SPONGEBOB-SAN.
- 欢迎来到我的岛屿，
海绵宝宝桑。
- OH, THANK YOU.
-哦，谢谢。
- I AM MASTER UDON.
- 我是乌冬面大师。
- HOWDY, MASTER UDON.
SANDY CHEEKS.
- 你好，乌冬面大师。
沙色的脸颊。
I DO A LITTLE KARATE MYSELF.
我自己也学过一点空手道。
- SANDY, SANDY, SANDY.
- 桑迪，桑迪，桑迪。
MR. UDON ISN'T INTERESTED
IN A KARATE NOVICE LIKE YOU.
先生。乌冬面不感兴趣
像您这样的空手道新手。
HE ONLY HAS TIME FOR ROYALTY.
他只有时间享受王权。
- OH, BROTHER.
- 哦，兄弟。
- PLEASE,
SHOW ME SOME OF YOUR MOVES,
- 请，
给我看看你的一些动作，
MASTER SPONGEBOB.
海绵宝宝大师。
- YOU HEAR THAT, SANDY?
HE CALLED ME "MASTER."
- 你听到了吗，桑迪？
他称我为“大师”。
BRING ON YOUR BEST FIGHTERS!
带上你最好的战士！
I'LL TRY TO GO EASY ON THEM.
我会尽量对他们宽容一些。
- HIYAH!
-嗨！
[thugs growling]
[暴徒咆哮]
- SPONGEBOB,
YOUR KARATE'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH
- 海绵宝宝，
你的空手道还不够好
TO HANDLE THOSE SIDEWINDERS.
对付那些响尾蛇。
- PA-SHAW!
- 帕肖！
WATCH AND LEARN, SISTER.
观看并学习，姐妹。
[shouts indistinctly]
[含糊不清地喊道]
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
[last breath sputters]
[最后一口气]
- YUP, THAT'S HOW
THE KING OF KARATE DOES IT.
- 是的，就是这样
空手道之王做到了。
WHO'S NEXT?
下一个是谁？
- SOMETHING SMELLS
LIKE RANCID RODEO AROUND HERE.
- 有气味
就像这里的腐臭牛仔竞技表演一样。
[thudding]
[重击]
- EXCELLENT.
- 出色的。
TRULY, YOU ARE KING OF KARATE.
确实，您是空手道之王。
- THE ONE AND ONLY.
- 独一无二。
- WE MUST MAKE READY
FOR YOUR CORONATION.
- 我们必须做好准备
为您加冕。
- I'M READY
TO BE KING OF KARATE!
- 我准备好了
成为空手道之王！
[gong crashes]
[锣声响起]
- KING OF KARATE-SAN,
- 空手道之王，
IT IS TIME FOR YOU TO TAKE YOUR
RIGHTFUL PLACE
现在是您采取行动的时候了
正当的地方
ON YOUR THRONE.
在你的宝座上。
- MY THRONE.
- 我的王座。
- ALL RIGHT, UDON,
I'M ONTO YOU.
- 好吧，乌冬面，
我关注你。
THIS PLACE IS AS CROOKED
AS A DIZZY SIDEWINDER.
这个地方很弯曲
作为一个头晕的响尾蛇。
- COME, SANDY,
- 来吧，桑迪，
TAKE YOUR PLACE
NEXT TO THE KING
占据你的位置
国王旁边
AND SHARE
IN MY CROWNING ACHIEVEMENT.
并分享
这是我的最高成就。
clap!
拍！
BRING A SEAT
FOR MY AIR-BREATHING FRIEND.
自带座位
为了我呼吸空气的朋友。
- SPONGEBOB,
Y'ALL ARE GETTING A BIT WILY.
- 海绵宝宝，
你们变得有点狡猾了。
- OH, DO I DETECT
A NOTE OF JEALOUSLY, SANDY?
- 哦，我发现了吗
桑迪，嫉妒的意思吗？
- HECK, I COULD KARATE YOU
INTO A COUNTRY FIDDLE
- 哎呀，我可以给你空手道
乡村小提琴
WITH ONE PAW
TIED BEHIND MY BACK.
用一只爪子
绑在我背后。
- [laughing]
- [笑]
BUT WHO'S BEING CROWNED
KING OF KARATE?
但谁会加冕
空手道之王？
NOT YOU.
不是你。
- I'M GETTING OFF
THIS CRAZY TRAIN!
- 我要下车了
这列疯狂的火车！
[mumbling]
[咕哝]
- MASTER, DON'T WORRY
ABOUT HER.
- 主人，别担心
关于她。
SHE IS MISSING OUT ON THE
OPPORTUNITY OF A LIFETIME.
她错过了
一生难得的机会。
[laughs]
[笑]
LET THE CORONATION BEGIN!
让加冕开始吧！
- SANDY'S GONNA MISS OUT
BIG-TIME.
- 桑迪会错过的
伟大的。
[gasps]
[喘气]
click!
点击！
- THAT DANG SPONGEBOB.
- 那该死的海绵宝宝。
WHO DOES HE THINK HE IS?
他以为自己是谁？
I TAUGHT THAT YELLOW EGOMANIAC
我教那个黄色自大狂
EVERYTHING HE KNOWS
ABOUT FIGHTING,
他知道的一切
关于格斗，
AND THAT AIN'T MUCH.
这还不算什么。
- NO!
- 不！
- SPONGEBOB'S IN TROUBLE!
- 海绵宝宝有麻烦了！
[SpongeBob continues screaming]
[海绵宝宝继续尖叫]
SPONGEBOB IS
THE "KING OF KARATE."
海绵宝宝是
“空手道之王”。
HE DOESN'T NEED ME.
他不需要我。
EH, HE CAN HANDLE THIS HIMSELF.
呃，他自己可以解决这个问题。
- SANDY, I NEED YOU!
- 桑迪，我需要你！
I CAN'T HANDLE THIS MYSELF!
我自己处理不了这个事情！
- HOLD ON, BUDDY!
- 坚持住，伙计！
- NO!
- 不！
SANDY!
沙！
- SHE WILL NEVER REACH YOU.
- 她永远不会联系到你。
SHE MUST FIRST PASS THROUGH...
她必须首先通过……
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- THE FOUR FLOORS OF FEAR.
- 四层恐惧。
- SPONGEBOB?
- 海绵宝宝？
- HA.
- 哈。
HA-HA-HA.
哈哈哈。
YOU CANNOT PASS
你无法通过
UNLESS YOU DEFEAT ME,
THE TICKLER,
除非你打败我
烦人的事，
AND MY IRON-FINGER STYLE.
还有我的铁手指风格。
HA-HA!
哈哈！
HA-HA.
哈哈。
LOOK!
- HUH?
看！
- 嗯？
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
- PREPARE FOR
THE TICKLING OF YOUR LIFE!
- 准备
您生命中的痒痒！
TASTE THESE!
尝尝这些！
OH, NO!
哦，不！
JELLY-FILLED DOUGHNUTS!
果冻甜甜圈！
HOW DID YOU KNOW
THEY WERE MY WEAKNESS?
你怎么知道的
它们是我的弱点吗？
NO ONE CAN RESIST JELLY-FILLED.
没有人能抗拒果冻填充物。
HIYAH!
嗨！
STICKY AROUND.
粘在周围。
I'LL BE BACK WITH THE GLAZED.
我会带着玻璃回来的。
- I COULD USE A WET-NAP.
- 我可以小睡一下。
- ALL RIGHT, WHO'S NEXT?
- 好吧，下一个是谁？
- HALT.
- 停止。
NO ONE ADVANCES PAST ME,
LIP SERVICE,
没有人能超越我，
口头服务，
AND MY POWER-FLEXY
DYNAMO-LIP THRUSTER STYLE.
还有我的 Power-Flexy
发电机唇式推进器风格。
- HIYAH!
-嗨！
- DANCE, SQUIRREL!
DANCE!
- 跳舞吧，松鼠！
舞蹈！
[laughing]
[笑]
- ADVANCED HAIR-DRYER STYLE.
- 先进的吹风机风格。
- [laughing]
- [笑]
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT TO DO
WITH THAT?
你希望做什么
有了那个？
[whirring]
[呼呼]
OH, NO!
哦，不！
NOT CHAPPED LIPS!
嘴唇没有干裂！
OH!
哦！
[grinding]
[研磨]
crunch!
紧缩！
- THAT'S ENOUGH LIP OUT OF YOU.
- 你已经说得够多了。
[crunching]
[嘎吱嘎吱]
[shatters]
[破碎]
WHAA!
哇啊！
- NO ONE HAS EVER MADE IT
TO THE LAIR OF FILTHY PHIL.
- 从来没有人成功过
到肮脏的菲尔的巢穴。
NO ONE PASSES EXCEPT ME.
除了我之外没有人通过。
NOW, FEEL THE STING
OF MY HORRIBLE BODY ODOR!
现在，感受刺痛
我可怕的体臭！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[pinging]
[ping]
[平]
- HA-HA, PHIL!
- 哈哈，菲尔！
YOUR FOUL STENCH CAN'T PERMEATE
MY FRESH-AIR DOME.
你的恶臭无法渗透
我的新鲜空气穹顶。
- FRESH-AIR DOME?
- 新鲜空气圆顶？
[inhaling]
[吸气]
MAN.
男人。
I REALLY DO STINK.
我真的很臭。
- HIYAH!
-嗨！
- YOU ARE
ONE IMPRESSIVE SQUIRREL.
- 你是
一只令人印象深刻的松鼠。
YOU EVEN MADE A COSTUME CHANGE.
您甚至还改变了服装。
- RELEASE SPONGEBOB!
- 释放海绵宝宝！
- NEVER.
- 绝不。
thud!
砰！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- HE IS FORBIDDEN TO LEAVE
UNTIL...
- 他被禁止离开
直到...
HE SIGNS THIS CONTRACT.
他签署了这份合同。
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- REAL ESTATE.
- 你在说什么？
- 房地产。
- YOU MEAN THIS WHOLE THING
WAS A SCAM
- 你的意思是整件事
是一个骗局
TO GET US TO BUY REAL ESTATE?
让我们购买房地产？
- YES.
- 是的。
IF THERE WAS
A REAL KARATE ISLAND,
如果有的话
真正的空手道岛，
I'D BE A MILLIONAIRE.
我会成为百万富翁。
- YOU MEAN
I'M NOT KING OF KARATE?
- 你的意思是
我不是空手道之王？
- NO.
- 不。
BUT YOU COULD BE KING OF CONDOS.
但您可以成为公寓之王。
HERE, LET ME EXPLAIN.
在这里，让我解释一下。
IT'S REALLY QUITE SIMPLE.
这真的很简单。
YOU SEE,
你看，
IF YOU INVEST IN A TIMESHARE
HERE ON CONDO ISLAND,
如果您投资分时度假
在康多岛上，
YOU CAN SEE YOUR EQUITY INCREASE
TENFOLD.
您可以看到您的权益增加
十倍。
PERHAPS YOU
AND YOUR YELLOW FRIEND
也许是你
还有你的黄色朋友
WOULD LIKE TO SET UP
A TIMESHARE PLAN?
想要设置
分时度假计划？
- DON'T DO IT, SANDY!
- 别这么做，桑迪！
- [chanting indistinctly]
- [含糊不清地吟诵]
HIYAH!
嗨！
I WON'T GIVE IN TO YOUR
TIMESHARE VACATION SCAM!
我不会屈服于你的
分时度假骗局！
- THEN GIVE IN TO MY FISTS.
- 那么就屈服于我的拳头吧。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
HIYAH!
嗨！
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
[smacking and groaning]
[咂嘴和呻吟]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
splash!
溅！
- YOU'RE IN THE SOUP NOW, UDON!
- 你现在在汤里了，乌冬面！
- SANDY, I'M SORRY
I ACTED LIKE A JERK BACK THERE.
- 桑迪，对不起
我在那里表现得像个混蛋。
THANKS FOR SAVING ME FROM...
感谢您将我从...中拯救出来
gulp!
吞口水！
BUYING A CONDO.
购买公寓。
- OH, SHUCKS, SPONGEBOB,
THAT'S WHAT FRIENDS ARE FOR.
- 哦，蛋壳，海绵宝宝，
这就是朋友的意义。
- I STILL HAVE ONE QUESTION,
THOUGH.
- 我还有一个问题，
不过。
DOES THIS MEAN
I'M NOT KING OF KARATE ANYMORE?
这是否意味着
我不再是空手道之王了？
- YOU ARE IN MY BOOK, SPONGEBOB.
- 你在我的书中，海绵宝宝。
YOU ARE IN MY BOOK.
你在我的书中。
NOW, LET ME TELL YOU
ABOUT REAL ESTATE.
现在，让我告诉你
关于房地产。
IT'S ALL ABOUT LOCATION...
一切都与位置有关...
- I'M HERE!
- 我在这里！
THE KING OF CLARINETS
HAS ARRIVED!
单簧管之王
已经到了！
[mysterious music playing]
【神秘音乐响起】
♪
[lilting ukulele music]
[轻快的尤克里里音乐]
♪